Guide to the Donald Ogden Stewart and Ella Winter Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1854-1980; Series I; 15.0 linear feet (15 boxes)
  - Donald Ogden Stewart Correspondence
    - Outhwaite, Anne Stewart, 1921, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Outhwaite, Charles P., 1919 (Box 2)
    - "P" general, 1955-1977 (Box 2)
    - Phillip Exeter Academy (Box 2)
    - Pound, Ezra, TL (photocopy) to Lincoln Steffens, undated (Box 2)
    - Powys-Lybbe, Anne, 1975-1980 (Box 2)
    - Poynton, Michael, 1979, undated (Box 2)
    - Punch, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
    - Putnam, H. Phelps (Howard Phelps), 1920 (Box 2)
    - "Q" general, 1959 (Box 2)
    - "R" general, 1952-1977 (Box 2)
    - "R"-"S" general, 1911-1937, undated (Box 2)
    - Robins, Robert, S., 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - Roland, Aurora, 1973-1974, undated (Box 2)
    - Roley?, 1919; 2 (Box 2)
    - Rothe, Edward and Marlene, 1961-1971 (Box 2)
    - Rumulin?, Reed A., ALS to Miss Marr, undated (Box 2)
    - "S" general, 1950-1977, undated (Box 2)
    - St. John, Donald and Ruth, 1968-1970, undated (Box 2)
    - Sarason, Bertram D., 1970-1972 (Box 2)
    - Seaver, Edwin, 1966-1969 (Box 2)
    - Smith, Matheson & Co., 1958, undated (Box 2)
    - Steele's Play Bureau, 1957-1959 (Box 2)
    - Steffens, Peter Stanley, 1941-1975 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden, 1937-1947 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden, TL to "Dear Sir", 1941 September 2 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden, letters to him from various people, 1941, undated (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden and others, 1943-1947 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden, from Donald Ogden Stewart, 1941-1965; 3 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden and Donald Ogden Stewart, Junior, undated (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden, correspondence regarding school progress of, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden, correspondence celebrating birth of, 1928 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, from Anne Outhwaite, 1905-1922 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, ALS from Beatrice Ames Tolstoy, 1931 March 23 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, from Bert Stewart with small prayer book, 1898 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, 1911, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, letters from Donald Ogden Stewart, 1905-1916, undated; 7 folders (Box 2)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, from Donald Ogden Stewart, 1911-1930; 7 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, letters from Gilbert Holland Stewart, Junior, 1898; 2 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, letters from Gilbert Holland Stewart, Senior, 1887-1909; 2 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, letters to Gilbert Holland Stewart and Donald Ogden Stewart, 1909-1911 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, ALS from Whittmore, 1912 February 18 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Clara Ogden, letters from various people, 1919-1930 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden, Junior and others, 1944-1946 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden, Junior, 1945-1947 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden, greeting cards and miscellaneous notes, 1952-1978, undated (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden, Junior, regarding education of Stewart and Ames Ogden Stewart, 1942-1944; 4 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden, Junior to Donald Ogden Stewart and Ella Winter, 1941-1977, undated (Box 4)
    - Stewart, Gilbert Holland, Senior to Gilbert Holland Stewart, Junior (Bert), 1891-1898 (Box 4)
    - Stewart, Gilbert Holland Senior to Donald Ogden Stewart, 1908-1912; 12 (Box 4)
    - Stewart, Gilbert Holland and Clara Ogden from Donald Ogden Stewart, 1911-1916; 5 (Box 4)
    - Stewart, Gilbert Holland, Junior to Donald Ogden Stewart, 1909-1911 (Box 4)
    - Stewart, Gilbert Holland, Junior to Gilbert Holland Stewart, Senior, 1912 (Box 4)
    - "T" general, 1955-1980, undated (Box 4)
    - "T"-"Z" general, 1918-1930, undated (Box 4)
    - Teuer, A.C., ANS to "Unknown", 1917 July 4 (Box 4)
    - Tighe, Hester Smith, 1918-1919 (Box 4)
    - Tho__?, Louise, ALS to Lawrence Tighe, 1919 (Box 4)
    - Thompson Banks Productions Ltd., 1957 (Box 4)
    - Tolstoy, Beatrice Ames, 1926, undated (Box 4)
    - Tolstoy, Beatrice Ames, and others regarding the Stewart children, custody matters, etc., 1944-1946 (Box 4)
    - Tolstoy, Beatrice Ames, and others (including Ames Ogden Stewart & Donald Ogden Stewart, Junior), 1936-1943; 2 (Box 4)
    - "U" general, 1942-1974 (Box 5)
    - United States Information Service, 1966, undated (Box 5)
    - United States Treasury Department, 1918-1920 (Box 5)
    - University of London, Department of Extramural Studies, 1953-1955 (Box 5)
    - University of Wyoming, Archive of Contemporary History, 1973-1978 (Box 5)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1955-1975 (Box 5)
    - "V" general, 1943-1979 (Box 5)
    - Vanity Fair, 1921 (Box 5)
    - "W" general, 1951-1976 (Box 5)
    - Wanamaker, Samuel, 1943-1976 (Box 5)
    - Ward, W., TLS to Mrs. Donald Ogden Stewart, 1928 May 19 (Box 5)
    - White, Katherine, 1971 September 22 (Box 5)
    - Whitehead, Robert, 1950 (Box 5)
    - Williams, Marshall H., 1974-1978 (Box 5)
    - Wilson, Edmund ("Bunny"), 1942, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Winter, Ella to Donald Ogden Stewart, 1961 June (Box 5)
    - Winter, Ella, from Donald Ogden Stewart, 1969 January- March (Box 5)
    - Wolf Popper Ross Wolf & Jones, 1973-1978 (Box 5)
    - Wolfert, Ira, 1948-1969, undated (Box 5)
    - "Y" general, 1975, undated (Box 5)
    - Yale University, 1912-1921 (Box 5)
    - Yale University, Association of Yale Alumni, 1974-1979 (Box 5)
    - Yale University Library, 1972-1979 (Box 5)
    - Young, Collier, 1976 (Box 5)
    - ZAIKS, 1955-1957 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence by first name "A"-"F", 1952-1978, undated (Box 5)
    - Correspondence by first name "G"-"L", 1951-1975, undated (Box 5)
    - Correspondence by first name "M"-"R", 1949-1974, undated (Box 5)
    - Correspondence by first name "S"-"W", 1954-1975, undated (Box 5)
    - ---, Adeline, 1911, undated (Box 5)
    - ---, "Tris", 1921 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence re: works
      - By a Stroke of Luck, 1953-1978, undated; 4 folders (Box 5)
      - The Crazy Fool, 1968-1969, undated (Box 5)
      - Festival, 1959 (Box 5)
      - Honour Bright, 1958 (Box 5)
      - Hotel Splendide, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
      - How I Wonder [in English, French, German], 1950-1956; 10 (Box 5)
      - The Kidders, undated (Box 5)
      - The Sullivan Brothers (Box 5)
    - Engagement and wedding congratulations (Donald Ogden Stewart and Beatrice Ames), 1926 (Box 5)
    - Fan letters, 1937-1941 (Box 5)
    - "Frazzle Top Farm," Upper Jay farm property, correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 5)
    - Invitations, etc., 1915-1917; 2 (Box 5)
    - Lecture notes, undated (Box 6)
    - Telegrams, circa 1915 (Box 6)
    - Yale University classmates (including "Gog," H. Phelps Putnam, and others), 1913-1918; 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Fragments of correspondence, undated (Box 6)
    - Unidentified correspondence, 1948-1977, undated (Box 6)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1854-1961; 20 (Box 6)
      Includes photographs and negatives
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1930-1949; 7 (Box 7)
    - Unsorted correspondence, includes some correspondence, notes, photos, newspaper clippings, printed ephemera, undated; 14 (Box 7)
    - Empty envelopes, undated (Box 7)
  - Ella Winter Correspondence
    - "A-Z" General, 1924-1946; 17 (Box 8)
    - "A-Z" General, 1924-1946; 2 (Box 9)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1934-1935 (Box 9)
    - Anderson, Sherwood, undated (Box 9)
    - "Art and the Stars" exhibition, 1942; 6 (Box 9)
    - Barr, Margaret, 1918-1925 (Box 9)
    - Bass, Charles, 1923 (Box 9)
    - Black, John, 1927 (Box 9)
    - Cannon, Edwin, 1917-1933 (Box 9)
    - Cohen, Ben, 1920-1923 (Box 9)
    - Cohen, I. Bernard, undated (Box 9)
    - College Poetry Society of America to Muriel Rukeyser, 1935-1943 (Box 9)
    - Copley, John, 1926 (Box 9)
    - Darcy, Samuel, 1938 (Box 9)
    - Davidson, Yvonne, 1924-1930 (Box 9)
    - Davis, Robert Gorham, 1937-1938; 4 (Box 9)
    - Decker, Caroline, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Ellis, Havelock, 1922-1923 (Box 9)
    - Fishback, Margaret, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1933 (Box 9)
    - Freeman, Joseph, 1931-1938 (Box 9)
    - Friday, 1940 (Box 9)
    - Guggenheim, Peggy, undated (Box 9)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1937-1940; 2 (Box 10)
    - Hayes, Roland, undated (Box 10)
    - Hickok, Guy, 1930-1937 (Box 10)
    - Hicks, Granville, 1937-1938 (Box 10)
    - Hofstadter, Felice, 1942, undated (Box 10)
    - Hollister family, 1927-1941; 2 (Box 10)
    - Howe, Mrs. Frederick Clemson (Marie H. Jenney), 1926-1932; 3 (Box 10)
    - Hudson, Martin & Ferrante (attorneys), 1937-1938 (Box 10)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1936 (Box 10)
    - Jeffers, Robinson, 1935, undated (Box 10)
    - Katz, Otto, 1942 (Box 10)
    - Kuckhoff, Greta, 1947 (Box 10)
    - Lewis, Grace Hegger, undated (Box 10)
    - Limebeer, Ena, 1920-1923 (Box 10)
    - Little, Brown and Company, 1945-1946 (Box 10)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1930 (Box 10)
    - Marshall-Hall, G. W. L., 1913-1923 (Box 10)
    - McWilliams Ethel Cole, 1918-1923 (Box 10)
    - Melville, Kitty, 1915-1917 (Box 10)
    - Myers, Roy and Charles Jackson, 1947 (Box 10)
      Regarding film "Fall of Valor"
    - The Nation, 1939-1946 (Box 10)
    - Ogden, C. K., undated (Box 10)
    - Orage, A. R., 1930-1931 (Box 10)
    - "Owen D. Young affair", 1932-1938 (Box 10)
    - Roughton, Roger, 1935 (Box 10)
    - Rowntree, Margaret, 1918-1920 (Box 10)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1934-1944 (Box 10)
    - Saroyan, William, 1936 (Box 10)
    - Singer, Paul, 1918-1919 (Box 10)
    - Smith, Paul, 1936 (Box 10)
    - Southard, Keith, 1936 (Box 10)
      Includes correspondence from third parties regarding Pacific Weekly
    - Steffens, Pete, 1943-1950; 2 (Box 10)
    - Steffens, Pete, 1943-1950; 5 (Box 11)
    - Steffens, Lincoln, 1929-1933; 6 (Box 11)
    - Steinbeck, John, 1936, undated (Box 11)
    - Stewart, Ames Ogden, 1949 (Box 11)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1944-1958, undated; 2 folders
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden, Junior, 1950 (Box 11)
    - Suggett, Laura, 1927-1930 (Box 11)
    - Taylor, Helen K., 1946 (Box 11)
    - Tolman, Ruth, 1940 (Box 11)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1943 (Box 11)
    - W. Colston Leigh Inc., 1946 (Box 11)
    - Welch, Marie de L. (Marie de Laveaga), 1933-1944; 3 (Box 11)
    - Wells, H. G., 1922-1923 (Box 11)
    - Wertham, Fredric, 1921-1940; 1 (Box 11)
    - Wertham, Fredric, 1921-1940; 7 (Box 12)
    - Wheelwright, Mrs. Joseph B., undated (Box 12)
    - Winter, Adolph, 1911-1922 (Box 12)
    - Winter, Freda Lust, 1924-1935; 9 (Box 12)
    - Winter, Rosa, 1926-1938; 2 (Box 13)
    - Winter, Rudolph, 1928-1940; 3 (Box 13)
    - Wolf, Lucien, 1922-1929 (Box 13)
    - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott, and Sara Bard Field, 1924 (Box 13)
    - Young, Art, 1942 (Box 13)
    - Young, Owen D. to Lincoln Steffens, 1915 (Box 13)
    - "England", 1917-1932; 3 (Box 13)
      Correspondents include: Wilina Gregory, Frances Levy, Marion Phillips, Ethel McWilliam, and Letty Lew
    - "Very Early", 1916-1925 (Box 13)
    - "Early and personal", 1921-1924; 2 (Box 13)
    - Family correspondence and juvenile writings, 1911-1921 (Box 13)
    - "Letters after father [Adolph Winter] died", 1923 (Box 13)
    - Letters from Steeple Claydon, 1915-1916 (Box 13)
    - Letters of recommendation, 1910-1923 (Box 13)
    - "Letters of introduction", 1923-1934; 3 (Box 13)
    - Letters regarding marriage of Ella Winter and Lincoln Steffens, 1924 (Box 13)
    - Letters regarding birth of Donald Ogden Stewart, Junior, 1932 (Box 13)
    - Letters regarding Lincoln Steffens' death, 1936; 3 (Box 13)
    - Letters regarding Lincoln Steffens' papers, 1936-1939 (Box 13)
    - Letters regarding "Beecroft Case", 1937-1939 (Box 13)
    - "Reds"; largely correspondence regarding Charles Baczsy, 1941 (Box 13)
    - Telegrams sent to Winter while in Russia (largely from Donald Ogden Stewart and Paul Tierney), 1944-1945 (Box 13)
    - "Letters Received in Russia", 1944-1945 (Box 14)
    - "The Week," "Russia Notes," and "Clippings", 1946 (Box 14)
    - Letters regarding Autobiography of Lincoln Steffens, 1945 (Box 14)
    - Fan mail, 1945 (Box 14)
    - "Fan mail: Berle Debate", 1948; 2 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence with publishers, 1948-1949 (Box 14)
    - Christmas cards, 1949, undated; 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Unsorted correspondence from 1941, 2 (Box 14)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1911-1946; 8 (Box 14)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1911-1946; 22 (Box 15)
- Writings, 1915-1975; Series II; 37.42 linear feet (38 boxes)
  Organized into four subseries: Donald Ogden Stewart Writings, Ella Winter Writings and Related Papers, Printed Material, and Writings of Others. Writings are arranged alphabetically by title.
  The series documents Donald Ogden Stewart and Ella Winter's writing careers with the bulk of material dating from 1915 to 1975. The series contains drafts, research materials, publicity materials, reviews, and some correspondence (related to particular works).
  The Donald Ogden Stewart Writings subseries documents various stages involved in the writing process, from first drafts to published versions. For Stewart's theatre and film work the subseries contains playscripts and/or screenplays, production files, printed materials, and photographs, that combined provide insight into various projects, such as How I Wonder and The Kidders.
  The Ella Winter Writings and Related Papers subseries includes research notes, drafts, printed versions, reviews, and other documents that provide evidence of Ella Winter's work as an author and editor as well as the career of Lincoln Steffens. Material relating to Winter's work as an editor, for example, of The Carmelite, can also be found in the Printed Material subseries. Some personal papers and other material are also located in this subseries.
  The Printed Material subseries contains published material by and about Donald Ogden Stewart and Ella Winter. The subseries also includes printed material about friends and family members.
  The Writings of Others subseries is comprised of drafts and printed versions of writings, often by Stewart and Winter's friends (Ernest Hemingway and Sinclair Lewis) and family members (Gilbert Holland Stewart).
  - Donald Ogden Stewart Writings
    - American Comedy (Box 16)
      - Typescript, with notes, undated (Box 16)
    - "An American in Hampstead," printed version, undated (Box 16)
    - Arms and the Man, 1941 October 8; undated (Box 16)
      Synopsis; First shooting script; First draft continuity script; Notes
    - Aunt Polly's Story of Mankind
      - Draft, undated; 2 (Box 16)
      - Review, 1924 February 6 (Box 16)
    - "A Ballade," draft, undated (Box 16)
    - "Brand New Moon," typescript, undated (Box 16)
    - "Boys of the Taft Room Grill," typescript, undated (Box 16)
    - By a Stroke of Luck!
      - Chapter CCVII and miscellaneous manuscript leaves, Before 1975 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous manuscript notes, Before 1975 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous manuscript pages, Before 1975; 4 folders (Box 16)
      - Notes for a new play shading into the autobiography, Before 1975 (Box 16)
      - Copy 1 xerox pp.1-143, Before 1975; 3 (Box 16)
      - Typescript (various incomplete drafts), Before 1975 (Box 16)
      - Copy 1 xerox pp. 143-698, Before 1975 (Box 16)
      - Xerox copy pp. 1-143, contains 3 unnumbered pages, Before 1975 (Box 16)
      - Typescript, photocopy, incomplete, Before 1975; 3 folders (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous fragments, typescript, photocopy, Before 1975 (Box 17)
      - Scrapbook of photographs, Before 1975
    - "The Cave", ms. and typescript drafts, undated (Box 17)
    - "Chaplin Profile" draft, typed, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 17)
    - The Crazy Fool (Box 17)
      - Draft, Before 1925 (Box 17)
      - Bound script, Before 1925 (Box 17)
      - Reviews, 1925 July (Box 17)
    - "Death of a Unicorn" draft, typed, carbon, corrected, and printed version in The New Statement, 1961 November 10, undated (Box 17)
    - "The Devil's Strip": typescript, undated (Box 17)
    - Dick and the Duchess, screenplay, undated (Box 17)
    - The Duchess and the Smugs, screenplay, first draft, undated (Box 17)
    - The Duchess and the Smugs, screenplay, notes, original story, undated (Box 17)
    - "Dregs", typescript, undated (Box 17)
    - The Escapades, final shooting script, undated (Box 17)
    - "Fat Smile" [skit] draft, typed, carbon, 1958 January 11 (Box 17)
    - The Father, script, 3 copies, undated (Box 17)
    - Father William, typescripts, two drafts, 1928; 2 (Box 17)
    - Festival, typescript with ms. notes, undated (Box 17)
    - Fighting Words, typescripts, various drafts, with related correspondence, 1940; 3 (Box 17)
    - Fine and Dandy
      - Notes and draft, undated (Box 18)
      - Script, undated (Box 18)
    - Flapperella, typescript, undated (Box 18)
    - "From Donald Ogden Stewart in London" [address] draft, typed, corrected, undated (Box 18)
    - "Genesis to Exodus" draft, typed, corrected, undated (Box 18)
    - Graustark, preliminary treatment, typescript, carbon, 1937 November 12 (Box 18)
    - Great Stuff!, typescript, 1928 (Box 18)
    - Gun Before the Butter, screenplay, typescript, xerox, undated (Box 18)
    - "Hemingway Script for BBC" draft, typed, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 18)
    - Holiday, final script, typescript, 1938 February 22 (Box 18)
    - A Hollywood Party, typescripts, various drafts, undated; 2 (Box 18)
    - Honeymoon in Reno, ms. and typescripts, various drafts, 1937 (Box 18)
    - Honour Bright, 1958
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: The Secret of the Gods
      - Typescript, 5 copies, Before 1958; 5 folders (Box 18)
      - Typescript, miscellaneous leaves with ms. corrections, Before 1958 (Box 18)
      - Notebook with some typed leaves and ms. corrections, Before 1958 (Box 18)
      - Photographs, undated; 2 (Box 18)
      - Scrapbook, 1958
    - "I Hope They Bury Papa From Summit Avenue" ms., undated (Box 18)
    - Hotel Splendide, typescript with ms. corrections, Before 1958 (Box 18)
    - How I Wonder (Box 19)
      - Script, New York version, act III missing, Before 1947 (Box 19)
      - Script, London version corrected copy, Before 1947 (Box 19)
      - Script, London version, Before 1947; 2 (Box 19)
      - Script, prompt copy, Before 1947 (Box 19)
      - Review, 1950 (Box 19)
      - Poster, undated
    - Ideas for television plays, misc. ms. notes, undated (Box 19)
    - The Investigator, script, 2 copies, undated; 2 (Box 19)
    - Joan of Arc, photographs and program, 1948 (Box 19)
    - John Brown's Body, ms. and typescript, with related correspondence, 1923 (Box 19)
    - Joy Boy
      - Script, act I, 1st draft, I.W. original, 1953 (Box 19)
      - Script, act I, 1953 (Box 19)
      - Script, act II, 1953 (Box 19)
      - Script, Ira's draft, carbon typescript, 1953 (Box 19)
      - Script, 1953 (Box 19)
      - Script, II, 1953 (Box 19)
      - Script, III, 1953 (Box 19)
      - Script, IV, 1953 (Box 19)
    - Keeper of the Flame, clippings, photographs, notes, and script, 1943; 3 (Box 20)
    - The Kidders
      - Typescript, carbon, 1950 (Box 20)
      - Bound scripts, 4 copies, 1950; 4 (Box 20)
      - Script, 1950 (Box 20)
      - Script for Italian version ( Sabbie Mobili ), 2 copies, 1950 (Box 20)
      - Manuscript pages 93-244, 1950 (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous manuscript and typed material, 1950 (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous ms. notes, financial papers, agreements, etc., 1950 (Box 20)
      - Scrapbooks of German reviews, 1950 (Box 20)
      - Scrapbook of photographs, 1950
      - Photograph of Arts Theatre Club, 1950
      - Photographs of production, 1950 (Box 20)
      - Posters, undated
      - Clippings, 1950 (Box 20)
      - Clippings, 1950 (Box 21)
    - Kitty Foyle, typescript, carbon, 1940 May 1 (Box 21)
    - A Lady between Lapps, screenplay, undated (Box 21)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1963 January 8 (Box 21)
    - "The Life of Karl Marx" draft A and B, typed, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 21)
    - Madam, Will You Walk, screenplay, first treatment (Box 21)
    - Mary Dean, ms., undated (Box 21)
    - Mary Lavelle, screenplay (Box 21)
    - "Mayo in Yale": ms., undated (Box 21)
    - "Meals I Remember," draft, typed, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 21)
    - Melba, script script with notes, ms. corrections (Box 21)
    - Men at Work, three drafts, typescript, 1943; 3 (Box 21)
    - Moment of Danger, script (Box 21)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Haddock Abroad
      - Draft, manuscript and typescript, carbon, Before 1924; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Outline to "Afterward", typed draft, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 22)
      - Correspondence with publisher, 1922 May 30 (Box 22)
      - Publicity, undated (Box 22)
      - Reviews, 1924 December 31 (Box 22)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Haddock in Paris, France
      - Two drafts, typescripts, Before 1926; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - New York Lady, typescript, 1930-1931 (Box 22)
    - The Other Day (Box 22)
      - Typescript, carbon, n.y. March 25 (Box 22)
      - Galleys, n.y. July 24
    - Our Feathered Friends, typescript, undated (Box 22)
    - The Outward Room, typescript, 1940 November 7 (Box 22)
    - "Paris" draft, typed, carbon, undated (Box 22)
    - A Parody of History, review, undated (Box 22)
    - Perfect Behavior in Hollywood, ms. and typescript, undated (Box 22)
    - The Perfect Fool, typescript, 1921 (Box 22)
    - Philadelphia Story, typescript, 1940 June 27 (Box 22)
    - Rebound, typescripts, two drafts; statements, 3 (Box 22)
    - Remote, typescript, carbon, undated (Box 22)
    - The Secret of the Gods, bound scripts, undated; 4 (Box 22)
      See also: Honour Bright
    - "The shades of night were falling fast...:" ms., undated (Box 23)
    - A Short History of the Cotillion, ms., undated (Box 23)
    - Smilin' Through, typescript, undated (Box 23)
    - Smith-Tighe, typescript, 1918? (Box 23)
    - Springtime, typescripts, two drafts, undated (Box 23)
    - Stamboul Quest, typescript, carbon, 1933 November 15 (Box 23)
    - "The Sullivan Brothers," sketches for possible tv scripts, draft, holograph, 1964 (Box 23)
    - Tales of Manhattan, typescripts, two drafts, 1941 September-October (Box 23)
    - "This is War." Program 6, typescripts, various drafts, with related correspondence and printed material, 1942; 2 (Box 23)
    - "Three for the Freshman" draft, typed, mimeograph, undated (Box 23)
    - Time of the Cuckoo, script, ms. notes, undated (Box 23)
    - Trop De Tailors (Hesitation Jerusalem), typescript, undated (Box 23)
    - A Voice from the Dead, typescript, 2 copies, undated (Box 23)
    - The White Sister, typescripts, various drafts, 1932-1933; 2 (Box 23)
    - Book reviews, 1954-1964, undated; 10 folders (Box 23)
      Books reviewed include: Drama and Commitment by Gerald Rabkin, Givers and Takers by Benjamin Appel, The Joys of Collecting by J. Paul Getty, The Benchley Roundup by Nathaniel Benchley, and In Debt by Leslie Bigelow.
    - Notebook on American humor, undated (Box 23)
    - Untitled manuscripts, draft, typed, undated; 2 (Box 23)
    - Untitled plays, ms. and typescript, undated; 3 (Box 23)
    - Untitled poems, ms., undated (Box 23)
    - Notes and fragments, manuscript and typescript, 1941-1967, undated; 10 folders (Box 23)
    - "Donald Ogden Stewart Manuscript List", undated (Box 23)
      List of manuscripts stored at Donald Ogden Stewart's home in England
  - Ella Winter Writings and Related Papers
    - "Sex Crimes/Ken", 1937-1938; undated (Box 24)
    - "Hollywood Today/Article NM", 1939-1940; undated (Box 24)
    - "Peace conferences: Paris, NY, Mexico", 1949; undated (Box 24)
    - "Chapter/Theater", 1944; undated (Box 24)
    - Rodell, John S. "Dawn on the Cape.", undated (Box 24)
    - "How It Looks to a Marxist", undated (Box 24)
    - Writings about comic books and related clippings, 1948; undated (Box 24)
    - Writings about mental hygiene, undated (Box 24)